"PONNIYIN SELVAN - PART 1"
A thousand years ago
before the dawn of the golden era
a comet appeared in the Chola sky.
Emperor Sundara Chozhar
who ruled in Thanjavur
had two sons and a daughter.
His eldest son, the crown prince,
the brave warrior, Aditha Karikalan
defeated the Pandyas on
the Sevur battlefield,
beheading their King Veera Pandiyan.
To avenge their king’s death,
Pandyan assassins infiltrated
the Chola kingdom,
vowing to destroy the Chola dynasty.
The younger prince, Arunmozhi Varman
had arrived in Lanka with his
vast fleet to win that land.
Meanwhile, the tempestuous
Aditha Karikalan
was leading an army to the north
to conquer the Rashtrakutas.
While his father, the Emperor,
lay ailing in Thanjavur.
The Emperor and his two sons
were in mortal danger.
In the sky the comet was baying
for royal Chola blood…
Rashtrakuta Nadu
My prince.
Fireballs!
The armoury is behind the east wall.
Destroy it!
Victory!
Victory is ours!
Hail to Prince Aditha Karikalan!
Prince, the king of the Rashtrakutas,
King Khottiga lies at your feet.
Khottiga.
I welcome a glorious death.
Hail to…
Go!
I will not slay another unarmed foe.
-Go!
-Aditha, kill me!
Sparing my life is condemning me
to a life without dignity.
Give me a glorious death.
Slay me!
Aditha, you’re making a grave mistake.
A wounded elephant is a tiger’s
mortal enemy.
The crown prince awaits us.
Come, Semba. Let’s go.
Salutations to the Chola crown prince.
Vallavarayan, you have bathed!
Nice clean clothes, flowers too.
Flowers of glory. At the tavern…
-Tavern?
-Not the tavern, the temple.
Is a winery nearby? Or a temple?
Give me your dagger.
Prince, will you dismiss me from
your army because I drank wine?
Your dagger, my friend.
I want you to go to Kadambur Fort.
My Prince, Parthibendran knows
the Chola kingdom well,
send him there. I'll stay here
with you.
On the next full moon,
an untoward event will take place
at the Fort.
Our spies have warned us.
Find out what they are plotting.
Will you go?
From there
journey on to Thanjavur
and inform the emperor.
My sister Kundavai is in
Pazhayarai Palace.
Tell her what you find out.
The Chola dam drapes
the sacred River Ponni
Crops blossom to the sound
of the flowing river
Stones sharpen to the sound
of the chisel
Bows stretch to the sound
of the enemy
All words flower to sing praise
of the Chola land
I must see the River Ponni
before the sun goes down
I must admire the lovely beauties
Silent as the breeze
Crossing barren lands
Crossing dusty lands
Crossing parched lands
Semba!
Where were you? I was worried.
Beauty makes me lose
the track of Time
-O land, as I lie upon your chest
-Lush green fields
Desires stir in me
Will Time turn in my favour?
Will my legs never tire?
O Semba!
I hear you galloping ahead
This lady Ponni
Singing softly as she flows
Gallop away to the valiant Chola land
Jump with joy!
Swift like the flowing river
My friend, go!
Fulfil our dreams
I must see the River Ponni
before the sun goes down
I must admire all the beauties
Silent as the breeze
O fair-skinned beauty
Dwell in my heart
O mischievous lady
Stay close to me
So much beauty to behold!
Ayya, who is that?
The most powerful Chola Chieftain,
Periya Pazhuvettarayar.
Asking such a foolish question
will get you thrashed.
Semba! Be quiet.
Fool! Your God has given you
clay for brains!
If my brains are clay, your whole
body is made of clay. Stolen clay.
Look at the sacred marks stacked like
50 clay pots on your brow.
Don’t speak of my sacred marks,
or I’ll pull your tongue out.
I have the power of six shastras in me.
I am Alwarkkadiyan Nambi.
Six shastras? I took your belly
for a mountain of appams.
Don’t you dare talk about my belly!
You charcoal pot!
You look like a clay owl!
All Gods are the same.
-Really? Are they all one?
-Yes!
Then the one God is Mahavishnu.
Shiva is greater.
Stop this quarrel!
Shiva and Vishnu are both Gods.
We are all gods. God is in you,
in me, in everything.
-So God is in this staff?
-Yes.
Watch as one God attacks another.
Ayyo, oh God!
Hey, tuft of hair. Big belly!
Then this sword is a more powerful god
than your staff.
Oh God!
He's killing me. I am Mahavishnu’s
fearless servant.
Fearless servant indeed!
Well, tell me now.
Who is the greater god?
Shiva? Or Vishnu?
When you’re sitting on me,
you’re the greatest of all.
Get up.
You seem strong and you look intelligent.
Let's settle this quarrel. Who is
the supreme God? Vishnu? Or Shiva?
I politely asked both Gods
the same question.
They said they were of the same height.
I even asked Brahma.
-You know what He said?
-What?
"Vishnu and Shiva are the same. Those
who do not believe it must eat mud."
I’ll thrash you.
Oh God!
Stop!
A brave warrior who carries
64 wounds from 24 battles.
The Protector of the Chola Dynasty!
The Treasurer! Here comes
Periya Pazhuvettarayar!
-He is Periya Pazhuvettarayar.
-I know.
Who is in the palanquin?
The Chieftain controls the Chola kingdom
and his young wife controls him.
Her name is Nandini.
She is his queen.
Ayyo! Who took my clothes!
-Who took them?
-Semba!
Semba. Stop!
-Thambi, can I ask you something?
-You’re greater than Vishnu.
-Go!
-It’s not about that.
Who are you? From where?
Where are you going?
Three questions. One reply.
Who are you to question me?
My name is Thirumalai.
Also known as Alwarkkadiyan.
My goal is to spread Vishnu’s glory.
I am a devoted Vaishnavite.
And my goal is to serve beautiful women.
I am a devotee of beauty.
So be it.
One more question. Are you going
to Kadambur Palace?
Kadambur Palace? Why would
I want to go there? Move aside.
A huge feast has been organised
at the palace today.
Periya Pazhuvettarayar is on his way.
There will be music, dance
and other festivities.
I’ve always wanted to see
Devaralan dance.
Semba, I'll sell you.
Take me there as your servant.
I will be most obedient.
Thambi, if you will not take me there,
-may I request something?
-What?
Will you give the lady in the palanquin
a message from me?
With a belly like yours, you plan
to romance a woman?
Semba, let’s go before we burst
his belly.
Wait! Take me with you.
Thambi! Brother!
Go! Make your way there!
You won’t get past the Fort gates.
Shame on you!
You disguise yourself as a holy man
and assault women?
-Sweet mother!
-Clear off! You with your tuft of hair.
Kadambur
Stop! Stop!
He does not have an invitation.
What do you want? Your name?
Vallavarayan Vanthiyathevan
from Vallam. Arayan is my title.
-He says he's Vallava…or something.
-Whoever he is,
we have orders to keep
the gates shut.
Your Prince Kandhamaran is my friend.
We fought against the Rashtrakutas.
200,000 soldiers fought
alongside the prince.
Thousands of donkeys too.
Is this one of those donkeys?
Let go of my horse. I’m going.
This donkey has quite a temper.
Let go!
Semba, charge!
Look!
Red, red, red, red!
Crimson red
Kandhamaran. Kandhamaran!
You invited me! Where are you?
Step back!
Red, red, red, red!
Crimson red
Kandhamaran! Where are you?
Kandhamaran!
Vanthiyathevan, is that you?
Now it’s bound to rain in Kadambur.
-Welcome!
-At last!
Find the evil spirits!
Fell them with a sword
Was he the man making trouble?
All around us is war, war!
Blood is boiling
-Who is he?
-A dear friend.
Vanthiyathevan. A Vanar Clan prince.
The Vanar Clan? In whose army do you fight?
I fought alongside the crown prince
in the Rashtrakuta war.
But I am no longer in his army.
I am here.
They say you have sixty-four battle scars.
Don’t you believe it?
Want to count them?
We grew up on tales of your bravery.
You have a way with words.
Go, watch Devaralan dance.
O Red-hued Lord!
O Lord of the Spear
O Broad-shouldered warrior
O Protector of our clans
O Lord Muruga
The Lord who wields the Spear
O King of Kings with steadfast spear
Grace us with your auspicious words
Will the rains fall?
Will the kingdom prosper?
Will the glory of our ruler endure?
Will our people thrive?
The Goddess seeks the blood
of royal descent
Crimson red, crimson red.
Red blood pours
The Goddess seeks the blood
of royal descent
Crimson red. Red blood pours
Play the drum if you wish
to destroy your enemies
Spill the blood of a man
of royal descent
The Goddess demands a sacrifice.
Blood must be spilled
The Goddess demands the king’s crown
The Goddess demands a young head
The snake, the raven.
Omen of death
The Goddess demands a sacrifice
The Goddess demands the king’s crown
The Goddess demands a young head
The Goddess demands a sacrifice
A sacrifice!
How did Sundara Chozhar
become emperor?
Gandarathidar had the right to be
emperor twenty-four years ago.
But he died suddenly.
So his nephew Sundara Chozhar
ascended to the throne.
It was not his birthright. We made
Sundara Chozhar emperor.
-We placed the crown on his head.
-True.
Because Gandarathidar’s son
Madhurantakan was a child then,
so we left the Chola kingdom in
Sundara Chozhar’s care.
But when Madhurantakan came of age,
the throne was not given to him.
Instead, Sundara Chozhar
anointed his eldest son, Karikalan,
the crown prince.
The throne was Madhurantakan’s
birthright.
But it was denied to him.
Sundara Chozhar did not seek our advice.
Was anyone consulted?
Some were consulted.
He asked Sembiyan Maadevi
and Kundavai Devi for their advice.
No one consulted us Chola Chieftains.
Instead, he asked the women
in his palace.
-You find it amusing?
-Pardon me.
Something is concerning me,
and others share my concern.
What is it?
If he’s blamed for consulting women,
the same can be said of you.
We hear you consult your young
wife on many political matters.
Vanangamudiyar! Mind your tongue!
Who are you accusing?
I do not accuse falsely, but when
we speak of political matters,
why must your queen be present?
Your question is fair. I am honour bound
to answer.
Can you wait till our deliberation
is over?
Pazhuvettarayar, so what do we decide?
Should Gandarathidar’s son, Madhurantakan,
be emperor?
Or the grandson of Gandarathidar’s
younger brother?
What does the Chola land dictate?
Gandarathidar is the elder
of the two brothers,
-so Madhurantakan must be emperor.
-Will Sundara Chozhar agree?
If we all agree, I shall convince him.
What about Madhurantakan? I hear
the throne does not interest him.
-He is a fervent Shiva devotee.
-You shall soon see.
Vanangamudiyar, let me now address
your accusation.
Prince, will you kindly step out?
Meet the Chieftains who wish
to make you emperor.
Prince Madhurantakan Devar!
Long live Prince Madhurantakan.
Long live the Shiva devotee!
Prince, was it you in the palanquin?
Is it the prince who graces
my humble abode?
Yes. I am Gandarathidar’s son.
I have a right to the Chola throne.
I seek your support in fulfilling
my destiny.
I value your support.
Hey, Vaishnavite!
-Alwarkkadiyan!
-Hurry! Row!
Let this rogue take the next boat.
Nambi, stop!
Hold the reins.
You there, big belly!
Thambi, mind your tongue!
But you responded when
I called you “big belly”.
Wait! I’m coming.
Start rowing!
Where are you going?
I hear they’re serving milk Pongal
at the Srirangam temple. What’s it to you?
With your big belly, you could’ve
fallen, scaling those high walls,
-and cracked open like a clay pot.
-Me, scaling? What high walls?
Nambi, if you don’t want to land up
in the river, out with the truth.
You play the devotee with
your sacred markings...
-Are they the props of a good actor?
-Blasphemy!
I’m a devotee of the Azhwars.
Nambi, the Kaveri is full of crocodiles.
They love tamarind rice-eating Vaishnavas.
Shall I throw you in?
If you hurt me,
Mahavishnu will not spare you.
Crocodile, crocodile!
Why did you scale the Fort walls?
The Fort walls? Who? Me?
Really?
Wait. I'll tell you why.
I was looking for you.
For me?
Yes...yes.
They refused to let me in
and I cannot wield a sword.
I could’ve sung Azhwar songs. And if I had,
the guards would’ve kicked me.
What choice did I have? I had to scale
the walls to watch the dance.
-Did you see the dance?
-My arm!
I saw nothing. Only Devaralan’s bottom.
They were all bunched together
as though in a ritual.
They drew their swords and took…
What was really going on?
-So you saw nothing else?
-No. Did you see anything?
It looked like a prayer meeting.
How are you related to the palanquin lady?
Why send her a message?
Oh that? The palm leaf message.
The truth!
You’ll turn me into a fish if you keep
dunking me into the river.
In Pazhayarai, we lived next
to Ramanatha Battar’s house.
One day he found a baby
on his doorstep.
He called the child "Nandini".
She was like a sister to me.
I hoped Nandini would grow up
to become a devotee like Aandal.
But one day she left us and vanished.
Then we heard she had married
Pazhuvettarayar.
And I never saw her again.
That’s why I wanted to send her
a message.
What message?
"Lord Krishna is waiting for you."
Semba, there goes Madhurantakan!
Do you wish to see the prince?
Are you asking me why? So we can put
our strong limbs to use!
Move! My horse is blind.
Move aside! Move!
Prince, your men are manhandling
my horse.
Prince, save us!
You are…?
Speak up! Who are you?
Pardon me. Are you the Chieftain’s queen?
Tell me the truth.
Why did you barge into my palanquin?
Let go, brother.
Forgive me, Devi.
Alwarkkadiyan, who claims to be
your brother,
has sent you a message.
-Are you his servant?
-No, Devi.
I am Aditha Karikalan’s friend.
He asked me to go to Thanjavur.
Karikalan?
Yes. I fought alongside him in battle.
Very well.
Let’s not talk now. There are spies
amongst my palanquin bearers.
Come to my palace tomorrow.
Show them my Signet Ring.
They’ll let you in.
Thanjavur
Semba!
What a majestic Fort!
We'll build one just like it in Vallam.
-You dare mention Pazhuvettarayar!
-Are you a Pandyan spy?
- Who took my dhoti?
-Semba!
You fool! Not again!
Don’t show me your face. Go!
Don’t you dare follow me.
Does one get to heaven
even if the guards trample you?
No one can question the Velakara guards.
Aren't they Sundara Chozhar’s
personal bodyguards?
They're Pazhuvettarayar’s
puppets now.
Last week a boy got into trouble
for saying that. He is dead now.
-Who are you?
-The temple flower-man. Sendhan Amudhan.
-Can you take me to the emperor?
-Close the Fort gates!
Serving you tamarind rice is easier.
Who are you? The Pandyan emperor?
-What is this scroll for?
-I write poems.
Have you any ink?
I want to rewrite Chola history. I must hurry
before the gates close.
-You can’t go inside.
-I bet on my horse Semba.
If I come back, I’ll reclaim Semba.
If I don’t, you keep him.
Using a wager so I’d look after your horse.
Cunning!
I live near Thallikulathar temple.
What's your name?
My Commander,
I am innocent.
-Your name?
-Kadhirvelan.
They thought I was taking
Pazhuvettarayar's name in vain.
But all I said was
“Please repair my cart.”
-Are you the Pandyan spy?
-No. You’re mistaken.
Commander!
He tried to enter by showing us
the Signet Ring.
Let go! Commander, I come from Kanchi.
The crown prince has sent
a message for the emperor.
This scroll is for the emperor.
The other is for Princess Kundavai.
There’s nothing of significance
in it. I’ll give it to the emperor.
No. I was asked to hand
it over in person.
Don’t you trust me? Or did the crown prince
insist you do it?
No, it was your brother, Periya Pazhuvettarayar,
who insisted I hand it over.
You met my brother? Where?
-At Kadambur Palace.
-Kadambur?
He gave me this Ring.
-Why didn’t you say so?
-No one let me speak.
Take him to the emperor.
Commander, the Ring...
Vanquisher of the Pandyas, Cheras and
Lanka, may the emperor live forever!
Who are you?
Greetings, my Queen.
I am Vallavarayan Vanthiyathevan.
Prince Aditha Karikalan’s friend.
He bid me come here.
Karikalan has built a golden palace
in Kanchi.
-He hopes you will visit it.
-Forgive me, Your Highness.
The scroll was written by me.
It was a pretext to meet you.
The crown prince sent me here.
-How do I know you are his messenger?
-I wondered about that too.
He said, "The emperor will recognise
my messenger.”
He asked me to go to Kadambur
and tell you what I heard there.
Kadambur?
Your Highness, the Chola Dynasty
is in great danger.
Those who swore to protect it,
now plot to destroy it.
-Who plots? What do you mean?
-My Queen.
The Chieftains met at Kadambur Palace
under Pazhuvettarayar's leadership
to plot against your kingdom.
The crown prince sent me to spy on them
and then come to inform you.
-Why didn’t you go back to Karikalan?
-He ordered me to come here.
He said I must warn you
and let Princess Kundavai know too.
Did you really fight alongside my son?
Yes, Your Highness.
In the Rashtrakuta war.
It was my good fortune.
Did you use this sword?
No, Your Highness. This sword
belongs to the crown prince.
When I was leaving, he exchanged
his sword for my dagger.
-This sword...
-...was forged in my armoury.
I gifted it to him.
He sent it with you so I would know
you are his friend.
Your Highness, come to Kanchi
with me. You are in grave...
I am in grave danger, Your Highness.
I seek your protection.
I am the sole survivor
of the great Vanar Clan.
If you return my kingdom to me,
I shall serve you till I die.
Forgive me, Your Highness. He was
allowed in by mistake.
Commander, he is Prince Aditha’s friend.
He bids me visit Kanchi.
The Commander has read
the message.
I will reply tomorrow.
He is our guest.
Commander, take good care of him.
I shall indeed!
Your Highness, I must return
the sword.
Thank you, my Queen.
Where is the guest palace?
-You’ll see it soon.
-It’s beautiful.
You’ll sleep soundly there. Your meals
will be served on time.
Let me have a look around.
I’ll be back soon.
Who will face the Commander?
We’ll be dead if we let you go.
Follow me.
If this palace doesn’t please you,
there’s another underground.
Is that Velkarar’s army?
-Yes.
-Splendid procession!
Don't let him escape.
There he goes!
Forgive me, Devi.
-Can you take me to Pazhayarai?
-Thief! Thief!
Move!
Watch out!
Don’t be scared. I am a Prince!
-Mother, is that buttermilk?
-Yes, son.
Give me some.
Here.
To think I jumped over fort walls
for buttermilk!
How much?
It’s free.
Queen Sembiyan Maadevi’s gift
to the people.
Free? She is a most gracious Queen!
There’s the spy. Catch him!
Move!
-He is climbing up.
-Let's use the stairs.
This way!
He's running eastward.
Hey you! Catch him!
This is the crown Prince's sword.
I must return it.
Catch him.
He's trapped.
You have nine lives.
Oh God!
Climb!
Careful.
-What are you staring at?
-Is that really you?
Yes, it’s me. Who else could I be?
Careful, we may be seen.
Last time you had
a big moustache, right?
Nice question.
I will be bald the next time.
Move aside!
-Come. Devi is waiting for you.
-As you wish.
My angels!
-You invited him?
-Hush!
Whose paradise is this?
Devi, the Sorcerer’s assistant is here.
You?
Indeed.
What sorcery allowed you inside
at this hour?
No sorcery. I climbed up
a rope ladder.
If you had showed them my Ring,
they would’ve let you in.
Why enter like a thief?
I was escaping the Commander's soldiers
and I saw the rope ladder.
You mean Chinna Pazhuvettarayar?
Does he not have absolute power here?
I showed him your Ring.
Don’t worry. I didn’t mention you.
I said Periya Pazhuvettarayar
gave it to me in Kadambur.
But he did not believe me.
-Where is the Ring?
-I have kept it safely.
I would not lose a Ring
given to me by you.
You said Karikalan sent a message.
No. It was Alwarkkadiyan. He said
he was like a brother to you.
-He sent the message.
-What message?
He said: "Lord Krishna is waiting
for you."
I can no longer become a devotee
like Aandal. That is a long-lost dream.
I do not agree.
Why not?
If Lord Krishna were to see you,
would He not abandon Bhama
and Rukmini?
He’d even drive away His 16,008 wives.
Men often praise me to my face.
If you turn your back to me,
I’d praise you even more.
Enough! You certainly know how
to charm.
-Now you're praising me.
-Then turn your back to me.
I never turn my back in war
or before a woman. I stand fearless.
You can praise me to my face.
You are indeed a true magician!
A brave warrior who carries
64 wounds from 24 battles.
The protector of the Chola dynasty.
The Treasurer! Periya Pazhuvettarayar
has arrived in Thanjavur.
Why do you look upset, brother?
Vallavarayan Vanthiyathevan
came from Kanchi
with a message for the emperor.
How did he get inside?
He showed us the Signet Ring
that you gave him.
No! I did not give it to him.
So what was the message?
Only an invitation for the emperor
to visit Kanchi.
But I overheard the messenger warn him
of imminent danger.
Where is this messenger?
I intended to hold him prisoner,
but he escaped. We're looking
for him.
He cannot have gone far.
Why did I make you the Fort Commander?
Any fool can dupe you.
Shame on you!
Keep the door open.
The Pazhuvur lord is here.
-You did not tell me your name.
-It’s Vanthiyathevan.
-My title is Vallavarayan.
-And your kingdom?
The sky above, the earth below.
You can win your kingdom back.
It is not impossible.
Devi, I have no interest in ruling.
He had your Signet Ring.
That’s how he gained entry.
I gave it to no one.
How did he get it?
Who gave it to him?
-Who do you suspect?
-Your dear wife.
Mind your tongue or I’ll cut it off!
No!
-Get rid of her.
-Silence!
Do me a favour.
I give my life for beautiful women.
For you, I’d die many times over.
But now I must go to Pazhayarai.
I have a scroll for
the Chola Princess Kundavai.
What scroll?
I can help you escape from here.
On one condition.
The reply the Princess gives to this scroll
must be brought to me.
Will you do that?
Devi, it could be dangerous.
You will be rewarded.
And rewarded way beyond
your wildest dreams.
This secret passage will lead outside.
You’ll pass a treasure chamber.
Do not let the treasures there
tempt you.
I stand before a shining diamond.
Are you dazzled?
A little.
Who are you?
Glory to the Pazhuvur lord!
Where is my queen?
Where is Nandini?
Where is the Signet Ring?
-Have you lost it?
-Is that what brings you here?
Did you not come to see me?
-Who are you?
-The Sorcerer!
How do you know me?
You’re a Sorcerer and so am I.
See? I have the Signet Ring.
Let go! Someone’s coming.
Do you know the Ring's value?
Someone has stolen it.
He did not steal it.
I gave it to that soldier.
He is a spy, not a soldier.
I know. That’s why I gave it to him.
I met him near Thanjavur.
I realised he was a spy,
so I asked him to come here.
I wanted to know who he worked for
and why he came to the Fort.
He is Karikalan’s spy.
How did your brother find out?
Was it not my Ring that made him
suspicious?
But he still let him escape.
Did the Commander know
where the spy was going?
He was headed to see Kundavai
in Pazhayarai.
Once he meets her, he will bring
her reply to me.
Did I do wrong?
My eyes see only your beauty.
Your beauty veils your intelligence.
I am helpless.
Madhurantakan is on his way.
Salutations to the Pazhuvur lord
and Nandini Devi.
Welcome!
You no longer need to enter
through the secret passage.
You shall soon enter as emperor,
astride the royal elephant.
If Shiva wills it.
Ravidasan.
You’ve forgotten the promise you made
to King Veera Pandiyan,
and the oath we took
to avenge our king’s death.
I carry deep wounds.
I forget nothing.
Stop this play-acting! It is our
duty to destroy the Cholas.
Are you now enchanted by luxury
since becoming the Pazhuvur queen?
You are right.
I am enchanted.
Will you behead me for that?
Kani.
Here are the Lankan coins you asked for.
Go to Lanka and bring me
the young Prince’s head.
May Goddess Kottravai be aware of this
May Goddess Kottravai be aware
of the dead king's wrath
The brave Pandyas will wash
Your feet with Chola blood
The Pandyan kingdom is where
the Pandyan Emperor lives.
This forest is Madurai to us.
Behold Amarabujanga Pandiyan,
son of Veera Pandiyan.
He graces the Pandyan throne.
Beautiful dark-skinned Goddess Kali
Goddess of the waves, mountains,
the arts. Hail Kali!
Let us pledge our lives.
Glorious Kali. Grace us with victory,
Goddess Kottravai!
We pledge our lives to the Pandya flag!
We pledge our lives to
the Pandyan emperor!
the Pandya emperor!
For killing our beloved
King Veera Pandiyan,
we will sever the head of the
Chola Prince Aditha Karikalan.
-Our blood is boiling!
-Revenge!
Death to his brother Arunmozhi Varman!
Death to the Chola Emperor
Sundara Chozhar!
We’ll offer their blood to Kottravai.
We will! We will!
-Are you the spy?
-Hush!
I am the crown prince’s friend. That’s
why Pazhuvettarayar is after me.
I must go to Pazhayarai at once.
But I do not know the way.
-Come with me.
-Me?
-Who will conduct the temple prayers?
-Listen to me!
I must meet Princess Kundavai.
If you do not help me, I’ll be caught.
You’d be responsible for my death.
I will come back as a ghost
to haunt you and drink your blood.
Very well.
Pazhayarai
“Attention! A spy has escaped
from Thanjavur.
“If you see anyone acting suspiciously,
“alert the soldiers.
“The emperor’s command.”
I came to awaken your senses
I came to make you see sense
O Demon uncle! O Sun of the night
Don’t turn red in anger
Your sixth sense has lost all sense
O Demon uncle! O Sun of the night
Don’t turn red in anger
Your sixth sense has lost all sense
Warrior, warrior, warrior!
O mighty warrior
His bravery is as deep
as a banyan tree roots
-Salutations to Kundavai Devi.
-Sendhan, what is it?
I heard the announcement.
Are they looking for you?
Princess, I’m a poor temple flower-man.
Who’d be looking for me?
-They’re looking for a spy.
-A spy?
I met a man in Thanjavur.
Maybe it was him.
He was cunning. He even managed
to meet the emperor.
Made to destroy.
Made from a legacy of might
Here comes the king
with the face of Kamsan
The son of power,
eternal friend of Truth
Not unlike a pearl.
I am the unique and only son
O little boy!
I have won the universe
Conquered all kingdoms.
They are mine, O mighty emperor!
Is there anyone to equal me
in this universe?
O Wicked One. O Sorcerer!
Who is here?
I touch the oceans.
The mark on my brow is the sun
I parade around North Madurai
Can you not think?
Are you not strong?
I’m just a little child. Have you
no shame to shout and rule?
What did this spy look like?
Like a spy.
He claims to be the crown prince’s friend.
Sometimes he disguises himself
as the demon Kamsan.
Kamsan?
He insists that he must see you alone.
If you see the spy again…
Should I hand him in
and collect my reward?
No, bring him to me.
I have a task for him.
O Uncle!
O Demon uncle
Sister!
Boatman, careful.
A watery grave has been predicted for me.
King Kamsan, why did you want
to see me alone?
Sendhan Amudhan told me.
Kamsan will answer. But who you are?
Who did you want to meet
in Pazhayarai?
The Chola emperor’s daughter,
Karikalan’s younger sister.
Arunmozhi Varman’s older sister.
The illustrious Chola Princess
Kundavai Devi.
I bear all these titles with difficulty.
Demon Kamsan, why do you tremble?
Are you scared of water?
Kamsan? Scared?
Demons don’t swim in water.
We swim in a sea of flames.
I wasn’t trembling, I was dancing.
Princess!
What a transformation!
From demon to spy.
I had no choice.
Pazhuvettarayar is after my blood.
And that fake Vaishnavite Nambi
follows me everywhere.
Why were you looking for me?
Karikalan sent me to Kadambur, Devi.
A secret meeting has taken place there.
Prince Madhurantakan was taken there
in Nandini Devi’s palanquin.
I have only one question.
Did Madhurantakan agree
to the conspiracy?
He wished to be emperor.
The lust for power surpasses
the lust for beauty.
Very well. Where is my brother’s
message? Do you have it?
Yes, Devi. I wrote the message myself.
Coming empty-handed did not seem right.
Show it to me.
"This messenger is a great warrior..."
Such modesty!
Books say modesty must not
dwarf truth.
What book? The one you're writing?
Yes, Devi.
In the war against the Rashtrakutas,
did you not fight alongside my brother?
I was by his side. I killed over
a thousand soldiers.
All right. A hundred? Over fifty?
If I lower the number any further,
my bravery will be in doubt.
So shall I send you on a dangerous
mission, befitting a brave warrior?
Is that my reward?
After all, you are a brave warrior
and have slain over 50 soldiers.
That is true. I await your command.
I want you to go to Lanka.
Find my brother Arunmozhi and bring him
to me. Can you do that?
I will seek the Lord of Death,
if you command me.
Really?
I swear on you.
Very well. I command you
to jump into this river.
Not the river, Devi.
You’ll have the message for my brother
before you go.
But the crown prince is waiting
for me.
I shall let him know. He’ll wait for you.
And so will I.
There’s a reward of 1000 gold coins
on your head. Careful!
My life belongs to you, Devi.
I will stay alive to fulfil your mission.
King Kamsan!
Do me a favour.
When Lord Krishna Himself asks,
can Kamsan refuse?
Will you give Ponniyin Selvan
a message from me?
Certainly!
Go!
Salutations, Prince.
Salutations, mother.
Madhurantakan, is what I hear true?
What have you heard?
-That you wish to ascend to the throne.
-Mother, the throne belongs to me.
To you? Who told you that?
Your father gave it to Sundara Chozhar.
I want it back.
How can you take back what was given
by your father?
You raised me as a Shiva devotee
against my wishes.
I am not a Shiva devotee.
I am a king.
I am not a sheep for slaughtering.
The Chola throne belongs to me.
I am the elder.
My son, you do not know how to rule.
Karikalan and Arunmozhi
are great warriors,
while you can barely wield a sword.
Mother, I have the support
of many great Chieftains.
They have taken an oath to back
my claim.
I am your mother. You cannot have
the throne without my consent.
Your father commanded you
to live as a Shiva devotee.
You cannot stand against
Sundara Chozhar.
What kind of mother are you?
You stand by someone who has taken
my kingdom from me.
I will never let go of my right to the throne.
Even if my dead father were to
ask me, I would not heed him.
Here, have these prayer beads!
Break it down!
Nulambapadi
Charge!
Victory! Victory!
Aditha, now that we have won,
let us return home.
No! We shall defeat the Kalingas next.
Your kingdom is in danger,
we must go home.
Karikalan, anything can happen
at any time.
Your father, your brother
and you are unsafe.
There is a plot afoot to seize your kingdom.
That's why I sent Vanthiyathevan
to Kundavai. She’ll take care of things.
Aditha, your sister is skilled in politics,
but she lacks experience.
Victory is ours!
Do not underestimate Pazhuvettaryar.
This Chieftain is like a fierce lion.
An old toothless and clawless lion.
Do not misjudge an old man
who marries a young woman.
Especially one who has poison
in her blood.
Karikalan, you are the Chola
crown prince.
You must protect Thanjavur.
You are duty-bound.
-The kingdom is your responsibility.
-Enough!
I will not set foot in Thanjavur.
You and your brother must
protect the emperor.
Stop!
Enough, Grandfather!
Why are you so angry?
Angry?
Who is angry?
Prince, I’ve noticed you get angry
whenever she is mentioned.
So you’ve noticed? So what!
Forget her. That's the best solution.
Forget?
To forget her, I must first cut
my heart out.
She was mine from childhood.
She is Pazhuvettarayar’s wife.
Desiring another man's wife is a sin.
Parthibendran.
She married that old man...
because of me.
Her folded hands
looked like lotus buds.
Delicate as a flower.
A pure white flower.
I was the crown prince.
She was
someone who sang
at the temple.
The entire royal Chola family
turned against us.
My father warned me. But I did not
heed him.
Then one day,
she disappeared.
Nandini!
A man dies several times
in a lifetime.
That was my first death.
I saw her again.
Many years had passed.
We were waging war against
the Pandyan emperor.
Veera Pandiyan had fled
the battlefield.
We hunted him in mountains and forests.
I found him inside a small hut.
That was the day
I died for the second time.
I became a walking corpse.
This wine, song, blood, war!
All this is to forget.
Forget her, forget myself.
Everything I do is a struggle to forget.
Tiger flag, war flag.
Our flag flies high.
The flag flies high
The horse is raring to go
The stony heart is stirred
See the sparks fly on the battlefield
Face the enemy with swords
and spears
Go forth and fight!
Let the Tiger Flag soar high
in the sky
May the Chola Kingdom
rule the world!
The striped tiger never fears nor rests.
Chola! Chola!
The fierce tiger does not know defeat,
O disciplined one!
My love for this land makes me
senseless
My love for this flag makes me
My love for this wine makes me
senseless
That woman made me senseless
My love for this land makes me
senseless
My love for this flag makes me
My love for this wine makes me
senseless
That woman made me senseless
O Demoness!
You are my breath, my wound
My body is covered with scars
from the battlefield
But the scar she inflicted
stops my heart
Worry not! Pass me the wine
so I may forget
This man’s journey will never stop
Carry that sword and march on
A vengeful tiger never stops
With a smile in your heart,
celebrate with a drink
Come, my friend
Is this pleasure everlasting?
Is it wrong to desire?
We dreamed of winning the world
We faced many battles
We ignored the Lord of Death,
slayed our enemies
We forgave foes who surrendered
Punished those who opposed us
We imprisoned those
who ignored our warnings
The Chola Dynasty is our life.
Taught it. Chanted it. This mantra
Touch the clouds, reach for the sky
Go, Tiger. Claim the Himalayas!
The flag flies high
The horse is raring to go
The stony heart is stirred
See the sparks fly on the battlefield
The flag flies high
The horse is raring to go
The stony heart is stirred
See the sparks fly on the battlefield
I beg you.
Spare his life.
Nandini.
No!
Lanka
Soldiers, alert!
Charge!
Wait! Wait!
Attack!
Make sure the prince is protected!
Victory is ours!
He has arrived.
The Vaithulya Bikshu Sangam
salutes the Chola Prince.
Master, you invited me, so here I am.
A comet has appeared in the sky.
We consulted ancient texts
to find out what it means.
A great king like Emperor Ashoka
shall rise among us.
You display all the signs of such a king.
The Maha Bodhi Sangam invites you
to be Lanka’s emperor.
This is the throne that once belonged
to Ashoka’s daughter.
All the kings of this island
are first anointed to this throne.
We give you
Throne, Sceptre and Crown.
Kindly accept.
Justice must prevail here. Lord Buddha’s
wisdom must rule.
This will all take place in your reign.
Accept the crown!
Accept the throne!
Master,
my father commanded me to bear
arms for the Chola kingdom.
As defender of the Chola kingdom
and servant of its people,
I cannot accept another crown.
I cannot defy my father’s orders.
So, I cannot accept God’s will,
or your request, Master.
I seek your blessings.
One who bows low is destined
to rise to the sky.
May you live forever.
May all your wishes come true!
Wait.
Let her come to us.
-Prime Minister.
-Princess.
Is all well? Has the emperor’s health
improved?
Chinese physicians are treating him.
He recovers well, my princess.
What concerns the people these days?
They ask why the emperor’s
daughter is still unmarried.
What did you say?
A noble prince worthy of the princess
is yet to be born.
By the time he is born and of
marriageable age,
I shall be an old woman.
She is like dark lightning
gleaming like a silver fish
Clashing with the roar of thunder
Can lightning and thunder co-exist?
O eternity, can these two forces co-exist?
Welcome, Princess!
Your arrival has turned this Fort
into a place of beauty.
I hear this palace has all the world’s
beauty within its wall.
You’re right. Beauty is indeed captive here.
Captive?
Does the golden beauty not adorn
the throne?
Yes, but the gold has faded.
Faded gold is the most precious.
Gold shackles are still shackles.
Are they not?
But the key is in our hands.
One cannot outwit the princess.
Welcome.
Father, our enemies are amongst us.
They want another crown prince.
Not Aditha Karikalan or Arunmozhi.
Karikalan’s friend said the same thing.
Who is conspiring against us?
Who do they wish to crown?
Your cousin. Prince Madhurantakan.
This conspiracy was planned
by Pazhuvettarayar
and the other Chieftains
at Kadambur Palace.
I cannot believe it.
Pazhuvettarayar raised me
with much affection.
But he is not the same.
Did you know the Chieftains
have come to Thanjavur in secret?
They plan to meet at
Pazhuvettarayar’s palace.
This passage is under
Periya Pazhuvettarayar's control.
Where does it lead to?
-Nandini Devi’s chambers.
-We must decide today.
-Welcome!
-My respects to Pazhuvettarayar!
Welcome!
Meeting in secret like thieves
is not right.
What if they find out?
Chinna Pazhuvettarayar,
do you not want Madhurantakan
to be the next emperor?
Your presence makes it legitimate,
Commander.
Princess Kundavai has asked Aditha
Karikalan to return to Thanjavur.
-He may come with a large army.
-We must act before he arrives.
Let us ask Sundara Chozhar
to hand over the throne
to Madhurantakan at once.
We’ll spread a rumour that the two Princes
march towards Thanjavur
to challenge their own father.
Sister, are we meeting Nandini Devi?
No. We shall meet the conspiring
Chieftains.
To imprison them?
-No. To unsettle their plans.
-How?
Through you!
Prince Madhurantakan must be crowned
without delay.
It must be done before
Aditha Karikalan arrives.
-We’ll inform the emperor tomorrow.
-We Chieftains have decided.
If the Princes join forces,
our plans will be ruined.
What is it?
-Princess Kundavai Devi is on her way.
-She is here.
The Princess is coming here?
Remain seated.
No need to worry.
It is quite normal for the Chieftains
to meet me.
She is like dark lightning
gleaming like a silver fish
Clashing with the roar of thunder
Can lightning and thunder co-exist?
O eternity, can these two forces co-exist?
May I come inside? Or do I offer
my respects from here?
The Princess is here unannounced.
There must be something important.
Please come.
Welcome, Devi.
Welcome, Princess.
My respects to you.
It’s rare to see you two brothers
together.
My respects to the Chieftains.
I was passing by when I heard
you were all gathered here.
So I thought I would stop by.
We were planning to visit you, Princess.
Before coming over,
we wanted to discuss
tax matters with the Treasurer.
That’s what brings me here, too.
We must lower certain taxes.
Why?
Princes Aditha Karikalan
and Arunmozhi
are to marry soon.
To marry?
-They are of marriageable age.
-And their brides?
We do not need to look very far.
You all have daughters.
There’s Manimegalai, your daughter.
Siriya Velaar’s daughter, Vanathi,
is here with me.
Vanangamudiyar, your daughter's name
is Madhavi, right?
My granddaughter’s name is Thirumagal.
My daughter is Thamarai.
There is no lack of brave women
in our kingdom.
If their horoscopes match those
of the princes, they’ll be chosen.
Is that not the custom?
Do not worry. Arunmozhi is yours.
There must be a commotion inside
by now.
“Commander, what is going on?
“Your grand plans have been
thwarted by a young girl.”
That wily Kundavai!
Must she always interfere?
No one in the Chola kingdom
is more cunning than she.
Get away!
Aditha Karikalan may arrive
with his army at any moment.
Kundavai has sent a spy to bring
Arunmozhi back.
If the two brothers return
together they shall seize
Thanjavur Fort together.
They will kill the emperor and claim
that it was your doing.
They will say you wished
to be the next emperor.
Let them come.
I can stand up to them. I have waged
countless wars.
Conflict within the Chola kingdom
will do untold harm.
A family conflict will give our enemies
the chance to enslave us.
It will be the end of the kingdom.
And the blame will fall on me.
There is only one way to stop it.
We must make sure Arunmozhi
and Karikalan do not unite forces.
Arunmozhi alone should be brought
to Thanjavur.
If the younger brother is inside the fort,
the elder brother will not attack.
I have a suggestion.
If you permit, may I share it?
Hey, boat girl!
Poonguzhali!
Are you playing with me?
I'll lose my temper.
A watery grave was predicted
for me. Did you know that?
Poonguzhali!
Does the moon not know
the depth of the ocean?
Will the eyes not reveal
the yearning of the heart?
Has that wandering cloud
lost its way?
Have you got spices and salt?
There's salt in the sea.
Fetch it yourself.
When will the horizon and the ocean
meet as one?
The waves have no markers
Hold this.
The light of the stars guides us
Poonguzhali.
Is Sendhan Amudhan your lover?
Did that silly flower-man say that?
If he said that to my face,
I’d throw him into the sea.
So, you’re not planning to marry him?
Why?
Sendhan Amudhan is my friend.
I cannot betray his trust, but…
But?
Do I stand a chance then?
Don’t be hasty. Put that away!
Do your work and I'll sleep.
-Is this the Lankan shore?
-Yes.
-What do you want?
-Will you do as I say?
Certainly.
I don’t believe promises men make.
I swear on the sea,
the sky, the earth and the eight
directions, I’ll keep my word.
-Are you meeting Ponniyin Selvan?
-Yes.
Ask him
if he remembers Samudra Kumari.
Is that your secret?
Is that what your heart yearns for?
Even if he does not ask about you,
I will remind him.
Poonguzhali, I’ve looked everywhere
for you. Where were you?
Is that Karuthiruman? What news?
I’ve struck a good deal
for the boat fare.
We need the money now.
Why?
-For the wedding.
-Whose wedding?
Your daughter’s?
Why didn’t you tell me?
Hey girl! You don’t realise my worth.
I’m talking about our wedding.
In your dreams! Why save money
for empty dreams?
Why did you come all this way?
To find medicinal herbs, tiger-claws
and elephant tail hairs for the emperor.
We must gather all our rebels in Thamballai.
Our mission is to kill Arunmozhi
as soon as we can.
Aadhan Maran, Soman and I
will look for the prince.
Varagunan, you look for
the Lankan King Mahindan.
Let me find Arunmozhi.
I will kill him.
No! You will ruin our mission.
What have you ever done?
Ravidasan, no!
I’ve never hesitated in taking a life,
or giving mine.
The time and the place must be right.
I will wait here.
I cannot enter without the
the emperor’s bidding.
It’s difficult to meet
Pazhuvettarayar these days.
Your Highness, I am your servant.
Until you are well,
your physicians have advised us not
to trouble you.
What if I never recover?
Will I not see my friend again?
Your Highness, we are here to obey
your command.
Is it true what I hear?
Madhurantakan wishes to sit on
the Chola throne? Is that right?
I also hear the Chola Chieftains
have chosen him as the next emperor.
I do not care who plots against me,
but my word will remain law.
Your Highness, I speak the truth.
Your sons compete with one another
for your crown.
Arunmozhi covets my crown?
Who claims this?
It may be a rumour.
-People are talking...
-Did you pull out their tongues?
You can stop these rumours.
Ask your sons to come here.
Let Arunmozhi declare his brother
the next emperor.
It’ll end all rumours.
True.
We have invited Karikalan to Thanjavur
many times, but he refuses to come.
Our messages do not reach Arunmozhi.
Periya Velaar stops them.
How do we make sure the princes
will come?
We must invite Arunmozhi.
Send him a message that
he must come,
or else he shall be arrested
and imprisoned.
-Imprisoned?
-It’s only an empty threat.
Imprison him? On what grounds?
The monks of Lanka offered
their crown to Arunmozhi.
He refused it. He did not have
the right to do so.
That crown belongs
to the Chola kingdom.
He owes the emperor
an explanation.
Explanation or imprisonment.
That is what we will tell him.
No. Then he’ll be condemned
for defying his own father.
He’s accused of that already,
my Queen.
Very well.
Issue my command.
How can a father imprison
his own son?
How is that possible?
It is my body that is ailing,
not my mind.
Then why?
I want Pazhuvettarayar
to be responsible
for bringing Arunmozhi here safely.
They might think they have
won this time,
but let my sons come. Then I’ll decide
what’s to be done.
Go to the northern border
and bring Karikalan here.
He has a reckless temperament.
Only you can make him see sense.
Why are you so downcast?
You want Arunmozhi to come,
don't you?
Yes.
When I hear them talking, I sense
they have a hidden motive.
Bring Karikalan to me. Go!
Captain, once you reach Lanka,
find the prince.
Give him the emperor’s orders
in person.
Arunmozhi's Commander-in-Chief
Periya Velaar must know nothing.
Captain, do you know what
the emperor's orders are?
My lord,
if my men know we go to imprison
the prince, they’ll revolt.
They must not know.
The emperor’s orders are only
for Ponniyin Selvan.
My lord.
Remember no harm should come
to the prince.
Let us set sail!
No!
Thamballai
That's too expensive.
Thambi, your guru is calling you.
Vanthiyathevan!
It's me.
So you’re my guru now?
With my sacred markings,
I can't say I’m your brother-in-law!
So, it’s guru.
You don’t need to bow.
I know you respect me.
Why are you here?
Are you people trained
in curing body ache?
Oh God. Let go!
Goddess Kottravai has sent
two guides to help in our mission.
-What are you doing here?
-The same as you.
I’m exploring this Buddhist town.
Why are you following me?
Who sent you here?
Vishnu came in a dream and said
He was weary of being in Srirangam
so He has come to Thamballai.
Lord Buddha is a form of our god.
But sadly,
without mace, sword or discus.
Nor can He fight.
-Are you saying Buddha is also Vishnu?
-Yes!
What else did He say?
Did He ask you to snore less?
Vishnu said
if I happen to meet a warrior
who talks too much,
I must save him and keep him
out of trouble.
Hey, Thambi! Did you see that?
I see Buddhist monks and beautiful
women with flowers in their hair.
Not them! I meant the mahout.
Alwarkkadiyan, when beautiful women
are looking at me,
why would I bother about
a mahout?
How irresponsible you are!
How did the Princess entrust you
with such a huge task?
-Why did you ring the bell?
-Vaishnavite!
-Can you come with me?
-This is what I was waiting for.
Come.
Nambi! Where are you going?
I’m coming too.
Go away!
-Is this a horse or a camel?
-Wait. I’m coming. Nambi!
Just wait.
-And a horse for me?
-I was asked to bring him alone.
We must follow them.
Lord Narayana!
Look after my bundle.
Stop!
-Give it back.
-Who is this scroll for?
Who are you? Give it back.
Or you'll answer my sword.
Ayyo, here!
Where's your sword now?
If you are a true warrior, defeat me in
a sword fight, then take the scroll.
Stop!
Delighted to meet you, Prince.
How did you know?
The fact you asked how I knew,
that’s how.
Long live Ponniyin Selvan!
Who are you? Why were you following
Alwarkkadiyan?
Prince, I am Vallavarayan Vanthiyathevan.
I belong to the Vanar Clan. I am
Prince Aditha Karikalan’s messenger.
Who owns this sword?
The Prince gave it to me and asked me
to see Princess Kundavai.
My brother gave you this sword
and asked you to meet my sister?
Yes.
Brave warrior!
Welcome to beautiful Lanka.
-Thank you.
-Did you enjoy my warrior’s welcome?
If you wish, we can resume
our sword fight.
I can’t fight you. I’m answerable to my sister.
-The scroll is written in invisible ink.
-How do you know?
What does it say?
You must come to Pazhayarai
at once.
Nambi, does nothing escape you?
All God’s grace! I am a mere servant.
Prince, I have another scroll for you.
-Guess who sent this one.
-Did you write it?
Prince, he’s a fake Vaishnavite.
It’s not God’s grace.
This message is from Princess Vanathi.
From the princess?
-Another of your skills?
-Hush.
She gave it to me without
Princess Kundavai knowing.
She didn’t want any fake Vaishnavite present
when you read it.
Nambi, let’s go.
- Your bundle!
- Thank you.
Shall we enjoy some fish?
Ayyo! Blasphemy!
I am a devoted Vaishnavite.
The One whose body is smeared
with holy ash.
The thief who stole my heart.
Prince, it’s safer for you to stay here.
That was the Prime Minister’s message.
Oh! So you’re the Prime Minister’s spy?
Princess Kundavai told me
to take you to Pazhayarai.
- Wait.
- You wait.
I gave my word to the princess.
The Pandyan rebels are everywhere.
You must be careful.
Prince, ignore him. He gets scared
even if I utter the word "crocodile."
-Say it then!
-Crocodile!
You want me to stay here.
And he wants to take me to Pazhayarai.
What does the emperor want?
Until he commands me,
I cannot leave Lanka.
You do not know
what is happening there.
The Chieftains and Pazhuvettarayar
are plotting against your father.
Lord Narayana!
My Prince!
Hail to the Pandyas!
For our king Veera Pandiyan
Claim your dead, Goddess Kottravai
Retreat! Retreat!
Lord Narayana!
Dear God!
Prince.
Stop screaming!
It’s only a tiny scratch.
A tiny scratch? My sacred thread
has been cut into two.
Nambi, who do you think attacked us?
They didn’t look like Lankan soldiers.
No, Prince.
It was the Pandyan rebels.
I warned you about them.
Prince, who rescued us?
Nambi, didn't she look familiar?
You must have hit your head!
He may be right.
I think she looked familiar too.
I agree with him.
I’ve seen that Oomai Rani before.
Do you know why people call me
“Ponniyin Selvan”?
Yes.
When you were young, you fell
into the River Ponni by accident.
Mother Ponni saved your life.
Thus… Ponniyin Selvan.
It was not Mother Ponni who saved me.
It was Oomai Rani.
When she pulled me out of the water,
I saw her face.
A face that is now etched in my mind.
It was she who saved us yesterday.
I realised she could not speak.
She was mute.
Who is she?
Why does she protect me?
How am I connected to her?
What do these cave drawings mean?
What mystery do they conceal?
I could not find out.
Mother, who are you?
Hail to the beloved daughter of the Emperor
Sundara Chozhar. Conqueror of Madurai.
Behold the Princess Kundavai.
She approaches!
This old man is weary of seeing
bloodthirsty soldiers.
To see my granddaughter is
as pleasing as sweet honey.
I seek your blessings, Grandfather.
Bless you.
Go, your brother is waiting for you.
Are you not Velaar’s daughter?
You were born to marry Arunmozhi.
The elders have fed this dream
into my heart for years.
Tomorrow if the prince changes
his mind, you are all to blame.
Until the day you marry Arunmozhi,
this old man shall not die.
Don’t make me wait too long.
You are the crown prince.
You must come to Thanjavur
to protect your father.
That is his wish.
Is that why he sent you
all the way here?
Everyone fears you, brother.
That is why I was sent
to take you to Thanjavur.
Until the Pazhuvettarayars reside there,
I will not come.
-Is it because of Nandini?
-No, because of you.
The emperor did not drive her out
of the kingdom.
You did.
Yes, I told the queen about her.
The Queen sent soldiers to throw her out.
-My life was ruined.
-It was for your own good.
You were jealous.
Her beauty and intelligence
put yours to shame.
She's an orphan.
She did not even know her lineage.
She could not be a Chola queen.
I am not just your sister but
also, a princess of the realm.
What matters to me are the Chola people.
None of us matter.
You took her away from me.
And turned me into a monster.
I was indifferent to her tears.
I turned her into a poisonous snake.
Since then, day and night,
she has continued to haunt me.
Aditha,
she is married. She is
Pazhuvettarayar’s wife.
Don’t I know that?
How could she forget me?
She once said she loved me.
Then she fell in love with Veera Pandiyan
and tried to save him.
And then she married this old man.
How could she?
I will not come to Thanjavur
while she is there.
I cannot.
Convince father and bring him to me.
I have sent Parthibendran
to bring Arunmozhi here.
He'll be here soon.
I’ll take care of the rest.
Arunmozhi will not come here.
He'll be brought to Thanjavur.
Orders were given to imprison him.
Soldiers have set sail to Lanka.
The emperor’s command.
A Chola ship!
Wait! I’ll go and see.
How many soldiers are there?
About thirty.
Are you from the Chola kingdom?
That ship doesn’t look like
a merchant ship.
Where can I find Prince Ponniyin Selvan
in Lanka?
Why do you want to know?
Do you mean you won’t tell me?
Who are we here to imprison?
Is your ship a prison ship?
Are we here to arrest Ponniyin Selvan?
They are Pazhuvettarayar's orders.
Lanka is under Periya Velaar’s command.
Pazhuvettarayar has no influence here.
Are we here to take Ponniyin Selvan
prisoner?
Why was this hidden from us?
The Chola people will not forgive us.
He is their treasure.
Turn the boats around!
Do you think I am here by choice?
It is the emperor’s orders.
We cannot disobey his command.
Where is King Mahindan of Lanka?
“Inside my turban.
“Why don’t you take a look?”
Rascal! You said you came to gather
medicinal herbs and I believed you.
Your greed brought us here.
Take me to King Mahindan.
“Over my dead body.”
Stop!
You will be richly rewarded.
King Mahindan will be rewarded too.
He cannot understand what
you’re saying.
“They’ll kill you before you
get near him.”
Do you want to see me die?
Or will you be the one who will die?
No, no.
I will take you to the Lankan king.
I need more coins for my trouble.
You must listen to me if you
want to meet the king.
Come.
Your Majesty, he attacked your camp.
He threatened to kill all your soldiers
unless they told him where you were.
I befriended him...
Tell him what you want.
I had to use these methods
to see the great Lankan king.
"You came seeking me.
Now die in my presence."
I have an important message.
A Chola ship arrived yesterday to take
Arunmozhi prisoner.
Sundara Chozhar ordered his men
to come here, my lord.
I saw them with my own eyes.
Arunmozhi Varman will be without
bodyguards and alone on that ship.
He’ll be defenceless at sea.
If you wish to win the war, you will
not get another chance like this.
I am a Pandyan rebel. I want
Arunmozhi Varman’s head.
Why didn’t you say that?
My lord, give me twenty boats
and fifty soldiers.
I’ll bring you Arunmozhi Varman’s
head and throw it at your feet.
I can see Pallava’s flag.
Periya Velaar’s men are approaching.
It's Parthibendran!
Salutations to Periya Velaar!
Vanthiyathevan!
It's me.
-You? Here?
-I am everywhere.
I heard you died at
Pazhuvettarayar’s hands.
I don’t believe I'm dead.
Your tongue is sharper than your sword.
Why not test my sword someday?
You haven’t changed.
I have come with orders from Karikalan.
What orders, Parthibendran?
You must come with me at once.
The Chieftains in Thanjavur
have turned traitors.
They are conspiring against
the crown prince.
No one can hope to win
against my brother.
I heard Aditha Karikalan say: “Only my brother
can defeat me.
“So he must stand with me.”
That’s why he sent me here.
Commander, what do you think?
Prince, a boat girl came with news
this morning.
A Chola ship has moored at
the River Thondaimaan.
It is here to take you prisoner.
-Where is this boat girl?
-Here.
Samudra Kumari, do you remember me?
How could I ever forget?
You once sailed in this humble girl’s boat.
I’ll never forget that day as long as I live.
Did you really see those
Chola ships?
-I overheard the soldiers too.
-What did they say?
They are Pazhuvettarayar’s men.
They have come with the emperor’s orders
to imprison you.
This is a conspiracy!
Maybe.
But if these orders carry the Chola
royal seal, I'm duty bound to obey.
This is folly.
There are only two occasions when
I must concede without question.
When father and ruler command.
And he is both my father and ruler.
Poonguzhali.
-I need your help again.
-Say no!
Command me.
I must go to the River Thondaimaan.
No, Arunmozhi.
-I can take you there.
-Hey, girl…
Prince, I implore you. Listen to us.
Prince, if you ignore us
and insist on going
then our army and I shall accompany you.
You must not stop us.
Vanthiyathevan, put on this turban.
Goodness! How can I?
It’s a Prince's turban.
Prince, ask anything else of me.
It's not a request.
It is an order.
It’s as though you had poured
molten iron on my head.
One day you’ll wear a crown.
A Chola princess will be sitting next to you.
I’ll be there too.
Consider this a rehearsal.
See that, devoted Vaishnavite?
Watch out!
The Chola crown has landed
on your head.
Keep your head safe.
-Poonguzhali.
-Yes, my lord.
Will you ride the elephant with me?
I am blessed, my Prince!
We are surrounded by
Periya Velaar's army.
Prince!
A prison ship is here. We must meet it
with full force.
The elephant has run amok.
Save the prince! Go!
Prince! Prince!
-Stop!
-Don't go alone.
Soldiers!
I am not the prince. Ponniyin Selvan
is riding the mad elephant.
It ran into the woods.
Find it. Go!
What a grand ship! So many soldiers.
Hey! Who are you?
I know many secrets.
I know why you are here.
I know what will happen.
Prince! Prince!
So why are we here?
To imprison the prince.
The young tiger is the first sacrifice.
Glorious Kali. Grace us with victory,
Goddess Kottravai!
The Goddess demands a sacrifice.
Blood must be spilled
Offer his blood to Kottravai.
Stop!
Who are you?
You imposter!
Instead of capturing the tiger's head,
we've captured its tail.
Brother…
Captain!
Prince, they’ve paid with their lives
for trying to imprison you.
Karuthiruman! What has happened?
They tricked me and fled
without giving me my gold.
-Who?
-The Pandyan rebels.
Captain!
He is not Arunmozhi.
Sorcerer, look carefully.
I am Arunmozhi.
You can see my crown.
Punish me. I have failed.
Punish me.
The turban fooled me.
Devaralan has failed. I have failed.
Stop!
To the shore!
Ply the oars!
My lord.
Poonguzhali,
the wind has stopped.
The prince!
Kottravai! Two heads for you today!
-Hail to the Pandyas!
-Hail to the Pandyan Emperor!
Prince, to the right.
Sail towards the ship!
Hail to the Pandyas!
My lord.
O Mother Ocean!
Prince!
O brightest Sun,
where have you disappeared?
I look all around the world for you
The River Ponni is waiting.
The Chola land is waiting
What is it, Vanathi?
What's wrong?
The moon is waiting.
But the Sun is nowhere to be seen
But the Sun is nowhere
to be seen
Where is my beloved?
Look at me. Speak!
-Is it Arunmozhi?
-Ponniyin Selvan...
What has happened to him?
The River Ponni has been orphaned,
Your Highness.
Where is my precious son?
Composure in trying times is
what makes a king a true king.
-Control your anger.
-This is not anger. It is bloodlust!
-To war!
-Think before you act.
This is Nandini's ploy. When I see her,
I shall behead her.
Aditha!
She is destined to die at my hands.
Or I’m destined to die at hers.
"PONNIYIN SELVAN - PART 1"
"PONNIYIN SELVAN - PART 2"
"PART 2"